Yes. Got the books. Let's go. Thank you.
>> I got you.
>> All right.
>> Yeah. Um, just man, I I just want to
start off saying I I love our team. I
mean, I love our people, everybody that
that that works on this like every year.
We're so blessed to be able to do this
and
like I can't tell you about the like the
coaches, the scouts, um medical,
everything that goes into this and then
you know all our guys like working the
phones today and like rookie free agency
and the whole process. It's just um we
have great people and um I'm very I'm
very personally very grateful and want
to say thank you to everybody through
the process. I gave you my phone.
>> I got it.
>> I got it. Well, it's going off.
>> So, yeah, with that,
>> go ahead.
>> No, it's your time.
>> You came in with four picks, come out of
it with as many players as you did and
the guys you got. Just how excited are
you with the moves you were able to make
to add to this class?
>> Yeah, fortunately, people don't want to
trade with us until like the sixth and
seventh round or fifth and sixth round
or some stuff like that. I don't know
why um that happened like that this
year, but um no, we were I felt like all
the way through we were targeted. We
were clear. We had a we had a plan and
uh you're always going to have some
upsets, you know, through throughout the
process. We had a couple of those for
sure. Um, but you know, the coaches were
awesome about moving forward after those
upsets and and the scouts and everybody
that was working the phones and what uh
the landscape or the board was looking
like and uh yeah, it was just ended up
just being a great process. We added
some we added some guys that like all
all the way through that were like,
"Okay, cool." like like there's a
there's a plan, there's a vision, um
there's a like collective feel for um
moving forward with these guys and how
they're going to compete with our with
our team.
>> Can you tell us about the decision to
move up for both Steven or move into the
fifth round for both Stevens? Yeah, it
was too big of a gap and u too much uh
too much talent there and and u both
came on a 30 visit and
uh we had you know we had a great it's a
really cool thing with the coaches right
like the you know just
you nodding like
>> I'm agreeing
>> it's like the yeah like the color
announcer from major league right there
um
>> take over man in the bag
>> no I mean [laughter]
>> fly ball
>> no it was a
>> [laughter]
>> No, just the process of coming in and
the coaching and Yeah.
>> How surprised
>> that he was still there in the fifth
round. Is that why you jumped in?
>> It was we just
>> uh Yeah, we were pretty surprised. Um
but
>> when it's the guy lasts that long,
you're like, "Okay, how do we how do we
figure this out?" And you know, we did
we did end up we did have a plan to kind
of play the um
you know, the you know, compensatory
game, if you will. And and uh [snorts]
so we were like, "All right, we have the
12 picks next year. What does it look
like?" So yeah, and the coaches just had
we had a lot of buying from the coaches.
They're really excited about them.
>> Mike, two two. Sorry, John.
>> No, thanks for asking Mike a question.
It's great. [clears throat]
>> Two men. They all like they were
energetic and self assured, but yet they
understood what it's going to take to
compete on a Super Bowl winning team. I
know there's like three things that are
in there, but you just seem to go
through all all new players that you
drafted.
>> Yeah, I think it's just again speaks to
just like the alignment with our with
our people and the things we're looking
for. But, um, you don't have to be like
that, you know, to be to be one of us
and for us to want you to want you here.
I think it's,
you know, so, but it's cool that it's
worked out that way. And, uh, and we got
great, like I said, uh, I think it was
day one, like we have great competition
on our team and, uh, we have a lot of
depth and be able to add some extra
pieces later in the draft is going to
be, uh, really fun to sort that out as
the process kind of unfolds.
>> Mike, you guys triple up at the
quarterback position, two seven riders
today. What are you excited about with
those two players, how they can fit into
that competition?
>> Yeah, well, there's definitely some
special teams value. Um,
but like you know,
you can never have too many corners, you
know, and I I don't think I've been a
part of a team that has this many like
drafted corners on their on their team.
And so, uh, going into camp, which is
uh, really exciting. So, it's going to
be a fun competition, man. You know,
it's going to be really cool to see um,
get these guys in here and get moving
and and see where it goes. So, um, and I
know Jay's really excited, too. Mike,
uh, you you guys didn't add an edge in
the draft. Um, uh, really appreciate
either. Talk about [clears throat] some
of the guys you've got on the roster
that maybe you think can step into that
role.
>> Yeah. Uh,
I mean, Jared Ivy's a guy that that's um
that had a great great season last year.
You know, he wasn't active as many days
as he probably wanted, but Jamie
Sheriff's another guy for two years,
been with us. Uh Conor Oul
um was up and does a lot of great
things.
Anybody
>> Gaines, we got Gains.
>> Yeah, Jaylen Gaines is back. Um so I
mean we're really excited about those
guys and they really worked really hard
last year and I think all of them were
ready to go if need be to go play in a
game. It just that's the way the roster
shook out on a week- toeek basis. Um, so
yeah, we're we're fired up about those
guys. And again, we're so early in our
like the draft kind of normally hits
first week of phase twoish. We're kind
of week ahead in terms of the process
when the players get here. So we're
early right now relatively speaking in
our process. So uh you know, we're off
to a great start. We got to keep keep
nailing these days with these guys and
and see see where see where it takes us.
>> And you guys after Monday and you can
sign free agents without it affecting
the comp pick formula. Uh, do you guys
anticipate maybe adding more to the
competition at the edge spot?
>> Yeah, we may.
>> Yep.
>> John, with OUL and Ivy specifically last
year, you've had some crunch points
throughout the year where you had to put
some guys on waiverss like the Anthony
and and Jared to not do that with with
Ivy and Oul. Does that kind of speak to
what you guys thought about them at the
time to expose them to potentially
similar?
>> Absolutely. Very good preseasons.
to credit to our uh you know our pro
[snorts] Willie and our pro personnel
staff with like identifying like hey
like these are the players that or these
are the teams are looking for a specific
position and [clears throat and cough]
excuse me and uh yeah was definitely
part of the process
>> with Emanuel Wilson. What would you like
about him? Is there some carryover with
like what Drake is? Yes. I mean, Jay,
this guy is an outstanding special teams
player and uh
Mike reminded me today he's, you know,
he's clocked at like 224, you know,
miles per hour with football pads on.
I'm not sure if you can run like that,
Brady, or not, but yeah, it's pretty
fast. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But, um, [laughter] no relation.
That's awesome. But, uh, well played,
sir. Um but uh you know he's I mean it's
just just a ton of speed and uh yeah
Jay's we were really excited to be able
to get Jay spent so much time preparing
for the draft and uh it was so great to
be able to get like like one of his very
top players he's excited about and fits.
>> John, you've over the years I thought
kind of expanded the amount
that
>> you've expanded the amount of people you
had making the draft calls. Why is that
important? You kind of share that with a
bunch
department.
>> Yeah, it's just a I mean, the scouts put
in they're they're away from their
families so much and you know like
Ryan's got two beautiful little kids.
He's gone all the time and they put in
so much time. It's just it's just a cool
thing. They they build these
relationships with these guys and um
it's just great for them to be able to
fin like finally say, "Hey man, we're
going to select you." and uh you know
hand the phone to the head coach and you
know I mean I feel very grateful that
I've been able to do this for a number
of years and you know I hope others in
our in our room will be able to do the
same thing you know be decision makers
and it's just fun to let them let them
do that and you know Bert's it's you
know we're going to be obviously the
team's going to be soul and so is Bert's
last last last draft with us and Becca I
mean she's like this girl works her tail
off and sorry young woman works her tail
off and uh so it was fun for her to be
able we were joking she kind of sounded
a little AIish but you know it was
pretty fun for her to be able to do that
too and it's just always backwards
people in the background that people
don't you know I get it you guys are
interviewing you know the players and
the coaches and every throughout the
year but there's a lot that goes in
that's behind uh behind closed doors.
Andre Fuller in particular was a guy
that it seemed like people thought might
go higher than you guys
point.
>> Yeah. But what did you guys like about
him? What you guys see him? It sounds
like he's got a lot of versatility what
he's done.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean it's I think just
looking at like an overall really good
football player and uh again going
through the process meeting with our
coaches
um you know it's it's trick tricky with
the multiple position thing but like the
ability to be able to do those things is
exciting. uh really smart just go out a
great football player you know he's
played on teams
>> special teams player as well
>> he had a great he had a great visit I
mean I I say that some guys don't have
great visits you know what I mean I feel
like I say that to you guys are like
this guy had a great visit and uh coach
>> coach is excited yeah you guys are you
know different area of the board
get him in the seventh round starting
defensive line.
>> Yeah, our coaches were were very excited
at a, you know, a gap player that can
get up and down the line of scrimmage
and has some upside as a pass rusher and
uh let's see what Patrick says about him
here. You guys will dig this analytics
talk here. Let's see.
Here's the analytics talk. Uh, young
player, solid stat line with a better
than average pass rush and a run game
production, good physical profile. These
are the analytic stuff we listen to all
the time. So it's going to Patrick put
this together for us. So I had to give
Patrick a shout out.
>> But no, he's this is this guy's a
monster. I mean, he's huge and like it's
a it's a really cool again came in on 30
visit. Coaches were excited. Scouts were
excited. Here we go.
>> Your guys' goal to get young players who
aren't in aw Super Bowl champion. What
do you think this weekend?
>> Good job. Yeah, I mean they wouldn't
have been on our board really. That's
that's a big that's a huge like uh they
weren't going to be on our board if we
felt that way.
>> How did that show
>> and I say that like the SC like like
that our scouts felt that way you know.
>> How did that show up in scouting? How
how because that's not I guess sometimes
>> I mean I could talk to you about this
for hours correct like these guys study
these guys forever. So it's like a you
know like there's we have a competitor
scale and like how they fit in the
competitor scale and what's their self
efficacy and like how are they going to
handle um competition?
>> John John with with Danby um he didn't
didn't have anything at the combine
proday kind of metric timing wise and
everything. What' you kind of learn
about him from from a number standpoint
through your process? What you could and
what can you kind of tell us about him?
>> Competitive, quick, sticky, and we felt
like, you know, we were missing out on
like not taking a DB from Arizona
because there was like I don't know how
many there was like seven of them taken
or something like that. So,
>> felt like we had to get in the mix. We
had some FOMO there.
>> No, he's he's a very competitive. I
mean, they had a great defensive
backfield. Um he came from San Jose
State and you know um yeah everybody's
really excited about him and he's one of
those guys too you know seventh round
you're getting closer to free agency and
it's like okay who are the guys that are
going to go well so
>> he he told us that um he's run in the
42s and
>> he's a quarterback. He's going to tell
you that. Yeah.
>> But does he's swaggy? Does that general
speed level kind of show up for you when
when you see him on tape? 42 twos or
whatever, but like it's there for you.
>> Yeah, he's fast. Fast. Quick. Yeah.
>> Like,
[cough]
>> excuse me.
>> It's been a rough weekend for Mike.
Cold.
>> Mike, a non- football one for you. What
did it mean to have your dad here this
weekend when
>> he over there?
>> Where's the old man?
>> Just giving his journey from the last.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's awesome. This is uh
shout out. Appreciate John for the way
we the way we operate here. It's it's uh
it's pretty unique. But yeah, it's been
awesome to have him here and
uh see him and him and Bill hang out and
figuring out the draft board and get the
binoculars out and solving the problems
and
>> um play a little golf, you know. Um but
yeah, anytime we get the chance to spend
time together is definitely chair,
especially where we're at on the map. So
it was really cool.
>> John, I know you're always confident in
the process. last year at this time
seemed like there's a lot more
uncertainty just in the playoffs a lot
of personnel turnover seems like this
year
seems to be more guilt of a complete
team going into training going into the
do you feel that way do you feel like
that
>> no I liked you mean like right now at
this time after the after the draft I
felt really good about our team Yeah, I
don't I mean, we're I feel I feel really
good about our team. I just have a
natural anxiety that that drives us to
constantly constantly be on the lookout
for how we can improve in every aspect
of our operation.
That's
yeah, that's basically it. like
>> you never ever feel like it's like it's
like oh yeah we're like you feel good
about your team and you love the guys
but there's a there's a part of our part
of our um philosophy is like what are we
missing [snorts] you know and and
like like how how do we get better? I
mean you know it's just how we roll.
>> Hey John, we were talking Josh Graph and
uh Ryan Florence earlier.
>> Oh cool. Awesome.
>> They've been with you for so long.
What's the benefit of having guys that
you have that much history with? And
then how do you incorporate new voices
uh to keep perspectives fresh?
>> Oh wow, new perspectives. Yeah, that's
great. Um yeah, there's a there's a
challenge.
So, first of all, the cohesion and being
able to be concise with your uh
communication and like quick, easy, non-
rambling. We don't read reports, you
know what I mean? you can just get at
things really quick, could solve
problems
just in a, you know, just in a in a
quick manner, quicker manner. Um, on the
flip side, the point about like what are
we missing out on is like there's always
this challenge of like, okay, well, you
know, there's a there's a possibility
this player could be this or, you know,
whether it's character, whether it's,
you know, off the- field stuff or, you
know, then on the field like the play
good and bad, you know, I've seen the
good. We we we basically try to uh
accentuate the positives. We've seen the
player do this. The easiest thing you
can do as an evaluator is say and the
safest thing you can do for your uh your
job's stability is basically say like
guy can't do this and he can't do that
and he can't do that. Okay. Well then
who you going to pick? Like somebody's
got to play, you know? So, it's just a
constant like, you know, just
inquisitive
challenge uh for these guys all the time
of like knowing at the end of the day
who the player is as much as they
possibly can, but at the end of the day,
when we bring them when we bring them in
the building, they still we're still
learning them. You know, there's guys
that have been here three years that
we're still trying to figure out like
not trying to figure out, sorry, trying
to help. on on uh Stephen. Do you see
him on the right side or the left side
or
>> um
No,
>> either side.
>> Thanks.
>> We'll figure all that out later,
>> John. Nice to be able to have the roof
in the room.
>> Oh, yeah. That was fun. Yeah. No, sorry.
I It's been a long weekend. I was like,
Stevens, huh? Sorry. Oh, Bo. Yeah.
Sorry. Uh
yeah, that was fun. Yeah, it was uh I
forget whose idea that was this morning.
It was pretty fun.
>> Anything else?
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, guys.
>> Thanks.